<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
	<string name="descriptive_help">
		<b>Descriptive Statistics</b>\n
		Provides the summary characteristics of a distribution.\n\n
		<b>Num of Samples: </b>	The total number of data points in the data set.\n\n
		<b>Min: </b> The smallest value in the data set.\n\n
		<b>Max: </b> The largest value in the data set.\n\n
		<b>Range: </b> The length of the smallest interval that contains all of the data. It is the difference between the maximum and the minimum value in the data set.\n\n
		<b>Sum: </b> The resultant of adding together every data point in the set.\n\n
		<b>Arithmetic Mean: </b> The sum of all data points divided by the total number of data points in the set. Commonly known as the average and is used as a measure of centrality for normal distributed data.\n\n
		<b>Geometric Mean: </b> An average derived by multiplying all the numbers in a data set and taking the <i>n</i>th root where <i>n</i> is the number of terms in the data set. This is useful in situations where simple addition is not descriptive of true mean. For example, when describing rates of return. NOTE: This only works for a pure positive set. NaN will result when negative values exist.\n\n
		<b>Lower Quartile: </b> Point that separates the lower 25 percent of data from the upper 75 percent.\n\n
		<b>Median: </b> The number which separates the lower half of the data set from the higher half. Used as a measure of centrality for skewed data.\n\n
		<b>Upper Quartile: </b>	Point that separates the lower 75 percent of data from the upper 25 percent.\n\n
		<b>IQR: </b> The interquartile range. This is the difference between the upper and lower quartile. This represents the distance between the top of the lower quartile and the bottom of the upper quartile.\n\n
		<b>Mode: </b> The value that occurs most frequently in a data set.
		<i>NOTE: </i> This currently returns 0 if none exists or otherwise the last occurence if more than one exists.\n\n
		<b>Standard Deviation: </b> Numerical value that describes how much variation there is from the mean. Low standard deviation means that data points are clustered very close to the mean. Higher standard deviations indicate the data points are spread out over a large range.\n\n
		<b>Standard Error: </b> A method of estimating standard deviation. Used when standard deviation of the entire population is not feasible to calculate and thus a sample is taken and used to calculate standard error as an estimation of the standard deviation.\n\n
		<b>Variance: </b> A measure of how far a set of numbers are spread out from each other. It is the standard deviation squared.\n\n
		<b>Kurtosis: </b> A numerical measure of the peakedness of a distribution. A higher kurtosis value means that a larger portion of the variance is the result of infrequent extreme deviations (i.e outliers).\n\n
		<b>Skewness: </b> A numerical measure of how skewed a distribution is. Equals 0 when the distribution is normal. Higher values indicate a higher degree of skewedness. Negative values indicate left skew data (longer left tail), while positive values indicate right skew data (longer right tail).
	</string>
	<string name="regression_help">
		<b>Linear Regression</b> \n
		A method of approximating the relationship between data points with given dependent (Y values) and independent(X values) variables. Approximates a line of best fit whose equation predicts any Y value given an X value.\n\n
		<b># of Data Points: </b> Total number of data points in the sample data set.\n\n
		<b>Equation: </b> Linear equation in the form of "y = mx + b". Where <i>m</i> gives the slope of the line, and <i>b</i> gives the y-intercept so that at any given point x, y = mx + b.\n\n
		<b>Mean Square Error: </b> A numerical value that is the average of the squared differences between the given data points and the predicted data points using a regression line. Used to quantify how accurate a line of best fit is. The lower the MSE, the more accurate the line of best fit is.\n\n
		<b>Y Intercept: </b> The point at which the regression line crosses the y axis, or where x = 0.\n\n
		<b>Slope: </b> Describes the steepness of the regression line. If slope is bigger than 1, as x increases, y increases at a greater rate. If slope equals 1, x and y increases at the same rate. If slope &lt; 1, as x increases, y increases at a slower rate. Slope can also be negative which means that y is decreasing.\n\n
		<b>Slope Std Error: </b> The standard error of the slope of the regression line. This value is higher when the data is more skewed.\n\n
		<b>R: </b> The correlation coefficient. A measure of linear dependence between 2 variables. Takes on a value ranging from -1 to 1.\n\n
		<b>R^2: </b> The coefficient of determination. A value ranging from 0 to 1 that describes the goodness of fit of a regression line. A value of 1.0 indicates the regression line perfectly fits and describes the data. As the value decreases, so does the goodness of fit of the model.
	</string>
	<string name="permcomb_help"> 	
		<b>Permutations and Combinations</b>\n
		Methods of calculating the number of different ways you can arrange a set of objects into a particular size of group.\n\n
		<b>Set Size: </b> The total number of objects\n\n
		<b>Group Size: </b> The size of the group in which objects are going to be put in.\n\n
		<b>Permutations: </b> The total number of non-repeating different arrangements of objects, where order of the objects matter.\n\n
		<b>Permutations with Reptitions: </b> The total number of different arrangements of objects, where the order of objects matter and objects can be used more than once.\n\n
		<b>Combinations: </b> The total number of non-repeating different arrangements of objects, where the order of the objects doesn\'t matter.\n\n
		<b>Combinations with Reptitions: </b> The total number of different arrangements of objects, where the order of objects doesn\'t matter and objects can be used more than once.\n\n
		<b># of Subsets: </b> The total number of subsets that can be made from a set. NOTE: This only uses the value given for set.\n\n
		<b>Pigeonhole: </b> The minimum number of objects that one group must have. For example if you have 10 objects in a set and 3 groups to put them in, then at least one group must have 4 objects. That is, it\'s impossible to arrange 10 objects into 3 groups without at least one group having 4 or more objects, making the result 4. NOTE: The value in group is being considered as the number of groups, not group size, for this function.\n\n
	</string>
	<string name="gaussian_help">
		<b>Gaussian Distribution</b>\n
		Also known as normal distribution. A continuous probability that describes data points that generally cluster around the mean of a data set. A perfectly normal distribution follows the 3 sigma rule: 68 percent of the data is within +/- 1 standard deviation of the mean, 95 percent of data is within +/-2 standard deviations of the mean, and 99.7 percent of data is within +/- 3 standard deviations of the mean. Commonly referred to as the bell curve, as the data takes the shape of a bell.\n\n
		<b>Mean: </b> The given mean of the population in question (see descriptive stats for more information).\n\n
		<b>Standard Deviation: </b> The given standard deviation of the population in question (see descriptive stats for more information).\n\n
		<b>X: </b> The given value for which you want to find a probability of occurrence. The raw value to be standardized.\n\n
		<b>Z: </b> The z-score value which is equal to the difference between a data point and a population mean divided by the population standard deviation. Z represents the difference between the given value and the mean in terms of standard deviations. Assumes a meaningful value between -4 and 4 that represents the probability of the given value occurring (probability derived from consulting a standard normal table).\n\n
	</string>
	<string name="poisson_help">
		<b>Poisson Distribution</b>\n
		Discrete probability distribution that yields a probability value for various outcomes for the number of events occurring in a fixed period of time, given a known average number for which the event occurs in the fixed period of time.\n\n
		<b># of occurences: </b> The desired number of occurences in a fixed time interval.\n\n
		<b>Lambda: </b> A given. The known average for the number of occurrences in a fixed time interval.\n\n
		<b>Probability: </b> \n\n
		- (X = x) represents probability of getting exactly the desired number of successes.\n\n
		- (X &lt; x) represents probability of getting less than the desired number of successes.\n\n
		- (X &lt;= x) represents probability of getting less than or equal to the desired number of successes.\n\n
		- (X &gt; x) represents probability of getting greater than the desired number of successes.\n\n
		- (X &gt;= x) represents probability of getting greater than or equal to the desired number of successes.
	</string>
	<string name="bernoulli_help">
		<b>Bernoulli Distribution</b>\n
		Discrete probability distribution that yields a probability value for various outcomes given a success/fail experiment that has a given probability of success (i.e. flipping a coin), a desired number of successes, and a given number of trials.\n\n
		<b># of Successes: </b> The total number of desired successes.\n\n
		<b># of Trials: </b> The total number of trials to be performed.\n\n
		<b>% Success: </b> The percent chance of succeeding in the success/fail trial(commonly the probability of success, but percent is used for convenience).\n\n
		<b>Probability: </b> \n\n
		- (X = x) represents probability of getting exactly the desired number of successes.\n\n
		- (X &lt; x) represents probability of getting less than the desired number of successes.\n\n
		- (X &lt;= x) represents probability of getting less than or equal to the desired number of successes.\n\n
		- (X &gt; x) represents probability of getting greater than the desired number of successes.\n\n
		- (X &gt;= x) represents probability of getting greater than or equal to the desired number of successes.
	</string>
	<string name="chisquared_help">
		<b>Chi-Squared Distribution</b>\n
		Renders a test statistics based on the sum of the difference of observed and expected values squared divided by expected values. Used with tables to determine statistical significance.\n\n
		<b>X^2: </b> The Chi-Squared value that results.
	</string>
	<string name="t_help">
		<b>The Students T-Distribution</b>\n
		Continuous probability distribution that is similar to a Gaussian distribution, however, it is used when mean is being estimated and true standard deviation is unknown. Uses standard error to estimate standard deviation.\n\n
		<b>Mean: </b> The given mean of the population in question (see descriptive stats for more information).\n\n
		<b>Standard Deviation: </b> The given standard error of the population in question (see descriptive stats for more information).\n\n
		<b>X: </b> The given value for which you want to find a probability of occurrence. The raw value to be standardized.\n\n
		<b>t: </b> A value similar to a Z-score in principle. It is an arbitrary value that, when considered with the degrees of freedom of the sample (equal to n-1), can be used in conjunction with a t table in order to determine the probability of X occurring given varying left and right tail significance levels.\n\n
	</string>
	<string name="datamanagement_help">
		<b>Data Management</b>\n
		The data management screen allows you to easily enter, store, retrieve,	and modify data for use within Stats Calc.\n\n
		<b>Storing Data</b>\n
		- Begin by entering a unique title for the data set. Thereafter, enter data in the X and Y text boxes.\n
		- To add another point, touch the <i>+</i> button.\n
		- To remove a data point, put your curser on the data point\'s text boxes and touch the <i>x</i> button that appears.\n
		- Touch the <i>Save</i> button to store the data using the chosen title.\n\n
		<i>Tips:</i>\n
		- The order of entering data points is irrelevant. Saving or selecting data will reorder points by increasing X values.\n
		- Multiple points with identical X values causes only the last point to be registered.\n
		- Invalid or empty data points will automatically be removed.\n
		- Using the same title as another set will overwrite the old data set.\n\n
		<b>Loading Saved Data</b>\n
		- Tap the title of the set you want to load from the column on the right.\n
		- Tap <i>Load</i> from the pop up menu.\n
		- The data will be loaded and will populate the column on the left.\n
		- You may modify and re-save the data under the same or different
		title.\n\n
		<b>Deleting Saved Data</b>\n
		- Tap the title of the set you want to delete from the column on the right.\n
		- Tap <i>Delete</i>	from the pop up menu and the data set will be removed permanently.\n\n
		<b>Selecting Data</b>\n
		- When you open Data Management from one of the Stats Calc functions, a <i>Select Data</i> button will appear.\n
		- After entering data or loading a saved set, tap on <i>Select Data</i>.\n
		- Data Management will close and the results will be shown in the Stats	Calc function you opened Data Management from.\n
	</string>
</resources>
